You may Enable/Disable the IDTE Entry from "Send to" context menu by using Configure IDTE-> Add IDTE Entry in "Send to" Menu.
You may enable the automatic updates By checking the "Automatically check for updates on startup" Option in Tools->Configure IDTE.
You may change the interface of IDTE by selecting the themes by using Tools->Configure IDTE->Themes Tab 
IDTE also allows fast tag editing mode for editing the tags without going back and forth in listview by using Tools->Quick tag editing mode
You may change the sources of fetching the lyrics by choosing >> button next to fetch button, and selecting appropriate source
You may disable or set the custom popups notification in notification tab by using Tools->Configure IDTE.
Default token scheme for filename conversion can be set in Tools->Configure IDTE->Other Settings and Check "Enable Default Scheme"  .
You may expport the tag information to various formats by using the export option in menu bar.IDTE supports export in TXT, NFO, CSV, XSPF ,HTML etc.
While playing files in IDTE, you may checkout the visualizations by selecting View->Visualization, and change them simply by clicking on them.
IDTE can be used as a complete music player by using the Player Mode Tab.Also it supports M3U,WPL,PLS playlists and CUE File with over 50+ Music Playback Support ,Various music visualizations and much more.
You may change the cover type of files, directly by right-clicking the cover art and selecting "set cover type"
You may checkout the Frequently Asked Questions by Using Help->FAQ's 
IDTE allows forcefully adding ID3 tag to any file.Just Select Tools->Configure IDTE->Advance and check Enable Forcefully ID3 Tag Editing.